[
    {
        "question": "1. How would you define Power BI as an effective solution?",
        "answer": "Power BI is a strong business analytical tool that creates useful insights and reports by collating data from unrelated sources. This data can be extracted from any source like Microsoft Excel or hybrid data warehouses. Power BI drives an extreme level of utility and purpose using interactive graphical interface and visualizations. You can create reports using the Excel BI toolkit and share them on-cloud with your colleagues.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. Power BI can connect to which data sources?",
        "answer": "The data source is the point from which the data has been retrieved. It can be anything like files in various formats (.xlsx, .csv, .pbix, .xml, .txt etc), databases (SQL database, SQL Data Warehouse, Spark on Azure HDInsight), or form content packets like Google Analytics or Twilio.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. What are the available formats?",
        "answer": "Power BI is available in various formats: Power BI desktop: For the desktop version\nPower BI mobile app: For using the visualizations on mobile OS and share it\nPower BI services: For online SaaS Power BI desktop: For the desktop version Power BI mobile app: For using the visualizations on mobile OS and share it Power BI services: For online SaaS",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. What are the available views?",
        "answer": "In power BI, you have various kinds of views viz: Data View: Curating, exploring, and viewing data tables in the data set. Unlike, Power Query editor, with data view, you are looking at the data after it has been fed to the model.\nModel View: This view shows you all the tables along with their complex relationships. With this, you can break these complex models into simplified diagrams or set properties for them at once.\nReport View: The report view displays the tables in an interactive format to simplify data analysis. You can create n number of reports, provide visualizations, merge them, or apply any such functionality. Data View: Curating, exploring, and viewing data tables in the data set. Unlike, Power Query editor, with data view, you are looking at the data after it has been fed to the model. Data View: Model View: This view shows you all the tables along with their complex relationships. With this, you can break these complex models into simplified diagrams or set properties for them at once. Model View: Report View: The report view displays the tables in an interactive format to simplify data analysis. You can create n number of reports, provide visualizations, merge them, or apply any such functionality. Report View:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. Where is the data stored in Power BI?",
        "answer": "Primarily, Power BI has two sources to store data: Azure Blob Storage: When users upload the data, it gets stored here.\nAzure SQL Database: All the metadata and system artifacts are stored here. Azure Blob Storage:  Azure SQL Database: They are stored as either fact tables or dimensional tables.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. What is a Power BI desktop?",
        "answer": "To access the Power BI features, visualize data, or model them to create reports, you can simply download a desktop version of Power BI. With the desktop version, you can extract data from various data sources, transform them, create visuals or reports, and share them using Power BI services.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. What are the different connectivity modes in Power BI?",
        "answer": "The three major connectivity modes in Power BI are: Direct Query: The method allows direct connection to the Power BI model. The data doesn’t get stored in Power BI. Interestingly, Power BI will only store the metadata of the data tables involved and not the actual data. The supported sources of data query are: Direct Query: Amazon Redshift\nAzure HDInsight Spark (Beta)\nAzure SQL Database\nAzure SQL Data Warehouse\nIBM Netezza (Beta)\nImpala (version 2.x)\nOracle Database (version 12 and above)\nSAP Business Warehouse (Beta)\nSAP HANA\nSnowflake\nSpark (Beta) (version 0.9 and above)\nSQL Server\nTeradata Database Amazon Redshift Azure HDInsight Spark (Beta) Azure SQL Database Azure SQL Data Warehouse IBM Netezza (Beta) Impala (version 2.x) Oracle Database (version 12 and above) SAP Business Warehouse (Beta) SAP HANA Snowflake Spark (Beta) (version 0.9 and above) SQL Server Teradata Database Live Connection: Live connection is analogous to the direct query method as it doesn’t store any data in Power BI either. But opposed to the direct query method, it is a direct connection to the analysis services model. Also, the supported data sources with live connection method are limited: Live Connection: SQL Server Analysis Services (SSAS) Tabular\nSQL Server Analysis Services (SSAS) Multi-Dimensional\nPower BI Service SQL Server Analysis Services (SSAS) Tabular SQL Server Analysis Services (SSAS) Multi-Dimensional Power BI Service Import Data (Scheduled Refresh): By choosing this method, you upload the data into Power BI. Uploading data on Power BI means consuming the memory space of your Power BI desktop. If it is on the website, it consumes the space of the Power BI cloud machine. Even though it is the fastest method, the maximum size of the file to be uploaded cannot exceed 1 GB until and unless you have Power BI premium (then you have 50 GB at the expense). Import Data (Scheduled Refresh): But which model to choose when depends on your use and purpose.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. What are the various refresh options available?",
        "answer": "Four main refresh options are available in Power BI: Package/OneDrive refresh: This synchronizes Power BI desktop or Excel file between the Power BI service and OneDrive\nData/Model refresh: This means scheduling the data import from all the sources based on either refresh schedule or on-demand. \nTile refresh: Refresh the tiles’ cache on the dashboard every time the data changes.\nVisual container refresh: Update the reports’ visuals and visual container once the data changes. Package/OneDrive refresh: This synchronizes Power BI desktop or Excel file between the Power BI service and OneDrive Package/OneDrive refresh: Data/Model refresh: This means scheduling the data import from all the sources based on either refresh schedule or on-demand. Data/Model refresh: Tile refresh: Refresh the tiles’ cache on the dashboard every time the data changes. Tile refresh: Visual container refresh: Update the reports’ visuals and visual container once the data changes. Visual container refresh:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. What are the major components of Power BI?",
        "answer": "Power BI is an amalgamation of these major components: Components of Power BI  Components of Power BI Power Query (for data mash-up and transformation): You can use this to extract data from various databases (like SQL Server, MySql, and many others ) and to delete a chunk of data from various sources.\nPower Pivot (for tabular data modeling): It is a data modeling engine that uses a functional language called Data Analysis Expression (DAX) to perform the calculations. Also, creates a relationship between various tables to be viewed as pivot tables.\nPower View (for viewing data visualizations): The view provides an interactive display of various data sources to extract metadata for proper data analysis.\nPower BI Desktop (a companion development tool): Power Desktop is an aggregated tool of Power Query, Power View, and Power Pivot. Create advanced queries, models, and reports using the desktop tool.\nPower BI Mobile (for Android, iOS, Windows phones): It gives an interactive display of the dashboards from the site onto these OS, effortlessly.\nPower Map (3D geo-spatial data visualization).\nPower Q&A (for natural language Q&A). Power Query (for data mash-up and transformation): You can use this to extract data from various databases (like SQL Server, MySql, and many others ) and to delete a chunk of data from various sources. Power Pivot (for tabular data modeling): It is a data modeling engine that uses a functional language called Data Analysis Expression (DAX) to perform the calculations. Also, creates a relationship between various tables to be viewed as pivot tables. Power View (for viewing data visualizations): The view provides an interactive display of various data sources to extract metadata for proper data analysis. Power BI Desktop (a companion development tool): Power Desktop is an aggregated tool of Power Query, Power View, and Power Pivot. Create advanced queries, models, and reports using the desktop tool. Power BI Mobile (for Android, iOS, Windows phones): It gives an interactive display of the dashboards from the site onto these OS, effortlessly. Power Map (3D geo-spatial data visualization). Power Q&A (for natural language Q&A).",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "1. What is a dashboard?",
        "answer": "The dashboard is like a single-page canvas on which you have various elements to create and visualize reports created by analyzing data. It comprises only the most important data from the reports to create a story. The visual elements present on the dashboard are called Tiles. You can pin these tiles from the reports to the dashboard. Clicking any element on the dashboard takes you to the report of a particular data set. Power BI Dashboard  Power BI Dashboard",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. What are the building blocks of Power BI?",
        "answer": "The major building blocks of Power BI are: Datasets: Dataset is a collection of data gathered from various sources like SQL Server, Azure, Text, Oracle, XML, JSON, and many more. With the GetData feature in Power BI, we can easily fetch data from any data source.\nVisualizations: Visualization is the visual aesthetic representation of data in the form of maps, charts, or tables.\nReports: Reports are a structured representation of datasets that consists of multiple pages. Reports help to extract important information and insights from datasets to take major business decisions.\nDashboards: A dashboard is a single-page representation of reports made of various datasets. Each element is termed a tile. \nTiles: Tiles are single-block containing visualizations of a report. Tiles help to differentiate each report. Datasets: Dataset is a collection of data gathered from various sources like SQL Server, Azure, Text, Oracle, XML, JSON, and many more. With the GetData feature in Power BI, we can easily fetch data from any data source. Datasets: Visualizations: Visualization is the visual aesthetic representation of data in the form of maps, charts, or tables. Visualizations: Reports: Reports are a structured representation of datasets that consists of multiple pages. Reports help to extract important information and insights from datasets to take major business decisions. Reports: Dashboards: A dashboard is a single-page representation of reports made of various datasets. Each element is termed a tile. \nTiles: Tiles are single-block containing visualizations of a report. Tiles help to differentiate each report. Dashboards: ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. What are content packs in Power BI?",
        "answer": "Content packs are packages comprising different Power BI objects such as reports, dashboards, datasets, etc. The two types of content packs are: Service provider content packs: Service providers such as Google Analytics, Salesforce, etc. provide pre-built content packages User-created content packs: Users can create their content packages and share them within the organization.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. What are the various Power BI versions?",
        "answer": "The three major versions of Power BI are as follows: Power BI Desktop: The free interactive tool that connects multiple data sources, transforms data, and creates visualized reports.\nPower BI Premium: The premium version is used for larger organizations with a dedicated storage capacity for each user. With premium, data sets up to 50GB storage capacity can be hosted along with 100TB storage on the cloud as a whole. It costs $4995 per month.\nPower BI Pro:  With the pro version, you get full access to the Power BI dashboard, creation of reports, along with unlimited sharing and viewing of reports. You also have a storage limit of 10GB per user. Power BI Desktop: The free interactive tool that connects multiple data sources, transforms data, and creates visualized reports. Power BI Desktop: Power BI Premium: The premium version is used for larger organizations with a dedicated storage capacity for each user. With premium, data sets up to 50GB storage capacity can be hosted along with 100TB storage on the cloud as a whole. It costs $4995 per month. Power BI Premium: Power BI Pro:  With the pro version, you get full access to the Power BI dashboard, creation of reports, along with unlimited sharing and viewing of reports. You also have a storage limit of 10GB per user. Power BI Pro:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. What is DAX?",
        "answer": "Data Analysis Expression (DAX) is a library of formulas used for calculations and data analysis. This library comprises functions, constants, and operators to perform calculations and give results. DAX lets you use the data sets to their full potential and provide insightful reports. DAX is a functional language containing conditional statements, nested functions, value references, and much more. The formulas are either numeric (integers, decimals, etc.) or non-numeric (string, binary). A DAX formula always starts with an equal sign. DAX  DAX A: Name of the project\nB: Start of the DAX formula\nC: DAX function (to add)\nD: Parentheses defining arguments\nE:  Name of the table\nF: Name of the field\nG: Operator      ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. What are the purpose and benefits of using the DAX function?",
        "answer": "DAX is much more than Power BI. If you learn DAX as a functional language, you become better as a data professional. DAX is based on different nested filters which magnificently improves the performance of data merging, modeling, and filtering tables.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. What is Power Pivot?",
        "answer": "Power Pivot enables you to import millions of rows from heterogeneous sources of data into a single excel sheet. It lets us create relationships between the various tables, create columns, calculate using formulas, and create PivotCharts and PivotTables. At a time there can be only one active relationship between the tables which is represented by a continuous line.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. What is Power Query?",
        "answer": "Power query is a function that filters transforms, and combines the data extracted from various sources. It helps to import data from databases, files, etc and append data",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. Difference between Power BI and Tableau?",
        "answer": "The major differences between Power BI and Tableau are: While Power BI uses DAX for calculating columns of a table, Tableau uses MDX (Multidimensional Expressions).\nTableau is more efficient as it can handle a large chunk of data while Power BI can handle only a limited amount. \nTableau is more challenging to use than Power BI. While Power BI uses DAX for calculating columns of a table, Tableau uses MDX (Multidimensional Expressions). Tableau is more efficient as it can handle a large chunk of data while Power BI can handle only a limited amount. Tableau is more challenging to use than Power BI.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. What is GetData in Power BI?",
        "answer": "GetData offers data connectivity to various data sources. Connect data files on your local system. The supported data sources are: File: Excel, Text/CSV, XML, PDF, JSON, Folder, SharePoint.\nDatabase: SQL Server database, Access database, Oracle database, SAP HANA database, IBM, MySQL, Teradata, Impala, Amazon Redshift, Google BigQuery, etc.\nPower BI: Power BI datasets, Power BI dataflows.\nAzure: Azure SQL, Azure SQL Data Warehouse, Azure Analysis Services, Azure Data Lake, Azure Cosmos DB, etc.\nOnline Services: Salesforce, Azure DevOps, Google Analytics, Adobe Analytics, Dynamics 365, Facebook, GitHub, etc.\nOthers: Python script, R script, Web, Spark, Hadoop File (HDFS), ODBC, OLE DB, Active Directory, etc. File: Excel, Text/CSV, XML, PDF, JSON, Folder, SharePoint. Database: SQL Server database, Access database, Oracle database, SAP HANA database, IBM, MySQL, Teradata, Impala, Amazon Redshift, Google BigQuery, etc. Power BI: Power BI datasets, Power BI dataflows. Azure: Azure SQL, Azure SQL Data Warehouse, Azure Analysis Services, Azure Data Lake, Azure Cosmos DB, etc. Online Services: Salesforce, Azure DevOps, Google Analytics, Adobe Analytics, Dynamics 365, Facebook, GitHub, etc. Others: Python script, R script, Web, Spark, Hadoop File (HDFS), ODBC, OLE DB, Active Directory, etc.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. What are filters in Power BI?",
        "answer": "Filters sort data based on the condition applied to it. Filters enable us to select particular fields and extract information in a page/visualization/report level. For example, filters can provide sales reports from the year 2019 for the Indian region.  Power BI can make changes based on the filters and create graphs or visuals accordingly. Types of filters are: Page-level filters: These are applied on a particular page from various pages available within a report.\nVisualization-level filters: These are applied to both data and calculation conditions for particular visualizations.\nReport-level filters: These are applied to the entire report. Page-level filters: These are applied on a particular page from various pages available within a report. Page-level filters: Visualization-level filters: These are applied to both data and calculation conditions for particular visualizations. Visualization-level filters: Report-level filters: These are applied to the entire report. Report-level filters:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "1. What are the various type of users who can use Power BI?",
        "answer": "Anyone and everyone can use PowerBI to their advantage. But even then a specific set of users are more likely to use it viz: Business Users: Business users are the ones who constantly keep an eye on the reports to make important business decisions based on the insights.\nBusiness Analysts: Analysts are the ones who create dashboards, reports, and visual representations of data to study the dataset properly. Studying data needs an analytical eye to capture important trends within the reports.\nDevelopers: Developers are involved while creating custom visuals to create Power BI, integrating Power BI with other applications, etc. \nProfessionals: They use Power BI to check the data scalability, security, and availability of data. Business Users: Business users are the ones who constantly keep an eye on the reports to make important business decisions based on the insights. Business Users: Business Analysts: Analysts are the ones who create dashboards, reports, and visual representations of data to study the dataset properly. Studying data needs an analytical eye to capture important trends within the reports. Business Analysts: Developers: Developers are involved while creating custom visuals to create Power BI, integrating Power BI with other applications, etc. \nProfessionals: They use Power BI to check the data scalability, security, and availability of data. Developers:  Recommended Resources Recommended Resources Power BI Projects Power BI Projects Power BI Resume Power BI Resume Power BI vs Tableau Power BI vs Tableau Free Data Science course Free Data Science course",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. What are the types of visualizations in Power BI?",
        "answer": "Visualization is a graphical representation of data. We can use visualizations to create reports and dashboards. The kinds of visualizations available in Power BI are Bar charts, Column charts, Line chart, Area chart, Stacked area chart, Ribbon chart, Waterfall chart, Scatter chart, Pie chart, Donut chart, Treemap chart, Map, Funnel chart, Gauge chart, Cards, KPI, Slicer, Table, Matrix, R script visual, Python visual, etc.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. What do we understand by Power BI services?",
        "answer": "Power BI provides services for its cloud-based business analytics. With these services, you can view and share reports via the Power BI website. Power BI is a web-based service for sharing reports. Power BI service can be best referred to as PowerBI.com, PowerBI workspace, PowerBI site, or PowerBI portal.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. What is the comprehensive working system of Power BI?",
        "answer": "Power BI’s working system mainly comprises three steps: Data Integration: The first step is to extract and integrate the data from heterogeneous data sources. After integration, the data is converted into a standard format and stored in a common area called the staging area.\nData Processing: Once the data is assembled and integrated, it requires some cleaning up. Raw data is not so useful therefore, a few transformation and cleaning operations are performed on the data to remove redundant values, etc. After the data is transformed, it is stored in data warehouses.\nData Presentation: Now that the data is transformed and cleaned, it is visually presented on the Power BI desktop as reports, dashboards, or scorecards. These reports can be shared via mobile apps or web to various business users. Data Integration: The first step is to extract and integrate the data from heterogeneous data sources. After integration, the data is converted into a standard format and stored in a common area called the staging area. Data Integration: Data Processing: Once the data is assembled and integrated, it requires some cleaning up. Raw data is not so useful therefore, a few transformation and cleaning operations are performed on the data to remove redundant values, etc. After the data is transformed, it is stored in data warehouses. Data Processing: Data Presentation: Now that the data is transformed and cleaned, it is visually presented on the Power BI desktop as reports, dashboards, or scorecards. These reports can be shared via mobile apps or web to various business users. Data Presentation:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. What are custom visuals in Power BI?",
        "answer": "Using Power BI visualizations, you can apply customized visualizations like charts, KPIs, etc. from the rich library of PowerBI’s custom visuals. It refrains the developers from creating it from scratch using JQuery or Javascript SDK. Once the custom visual is ready, it is tested thoroughly. Post testing, they are packaged in .pbiviz file format and shared within the organization. Types of visuals available in Power BI are: Custom visual files.\nOrganizational files.\nMarketplace files. Custom visual files. Organizational files. Marketplace files.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "1) What do you understand by BI? Or what is BI?",
        "answer": "BI stands for Business Intelligence. It is a technology-driven method that helps users analyze and visualize business data from thousands of data sources and share insights across their organization. It also provides important information that may help corporate executives, business managers, and other users make business decisions.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "2) What is Power BI?",
        "answer": "Power BI is a Business Analytics solution or a Business Intelligence and Data Visualization tool developed and maintained by Microsoft. It enables users to convert data from thousands of data sources into interactive dashboards, and BI reports.\nPower BI is a cloud-based Self-Service BI tool that collects applications, multiple software connectors and services used to organize raw data into important content.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "3) What is Power BI Desktop?",
        "answer": "Power BI Desktop is a free business intelligence desktop application installed on your computer. Power BI Desktop works with the Power BI service by providing advanced data exploration, shaping, modeling, and creating a report with highly interactive visualizations. By using Power BI Desktop, you can easily save your work to a file or publish your data and reports right to your Power BI site to share with others.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "4) What do you understand by self-service business intelligence (SSBI)?",
        "answer": "Self-Service Business Intelligence or SSBI is an approach to data analytics that enables business users to filter, segment, and analyze their data without the in-depth technical knowledge in statistical analysis or business intelligence (BI).\nThe motive of SSBI is to make data analytics easier for end-users to access their data and create various visuals to get better business insights. It is easy to use, and anybody who has a basic understanding of the data can create reports to build intuitive and shareable dashboards.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "5) What are the different parts of Microsoft's self-service business intelligence (SSBI) solution?",
        "answer": "There are two parts of Microsoft Self-Service Business Intelligence Solution:\nExcel BI Toolkit: Excel BI Toolkit is used to allow the users to create an interactive report by importing data from different possible sources and model data according to the report's requirement.\nPower BI: The Power BI is an online solution that enables users to share the interactive reports and queries you have created using the Excel BI Toolkit.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "6) What are the reasons behind the popularity of the Power BI tool?",
        "answer": "Following is the list of most important reasons behind the use of the Power BI tool:\nADVERTISEMENT\nPower BI provides pre-built dashboards and reports for SaaS Solutions.\nPower BI offers a secure and reliable connection to your data sources in the cloud or on-premises.\nIt also offers fast deployment, hybrid configuration, and a secure environment.\nPower BI allows real-time dashboard updates.\nIt uses a natural language query to help us in data exploration.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "7) What are the different important components of Power BI?",
        "answer": "The various Power BI components are:\nPower BI Service:\nPower BI Desktop\nPower BI Services\nPower BI Mobile\nPower BI Gateway\nPower BI Premium\nPower BI Report Server\nPower BI Embedded\nPower Pivot\nPower Query\nPower Map\nPower View\nData Management Gateway\nData Catalog\nPower BI Q&A\nThe components of Power BI are also classified as:\nData Integration\nData Processing\nData Presentation",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "8) What is Dax Function that is used in Power BI?",
        "answer": "Dax Function is a formula expression language used with various business intelligence visualization tools like Power BI. It is also known as a functional language, where the full code is kept inside a function.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "9) What are the different data types used in Dax?",
        "answer": "Following are the Data types used in Dax:\nNumeric\nBoolean\nDateTime\nString\nDecimal",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "10) What are the essential applications that use Power BI?",
        "answer": "Microsoft Power BI is mainly used by the following:\nBusiness & Data Analyst\nPMO - Project Management Office\nDeveloper & Database Administrator\nIT Team, IT Professional\nConsumer for End User Report\nData Scientists etc.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "11) Is Power BI hard to Learn for a fresher?",
        "answer": "Power BI is Microsoft's tool for data analysis and visualization. It doesn't require knowledge or experience of any programming language. A data analyst can quickly connect with any data source, summarizing the findings into simple reports without any programming experience. With Power Pivot built into the Power BI, analytics measures were developed using DAX query language from Microsoft.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "12) How Important is Power BI?",
        "answer": "Power BI is one of Microsoft's greatest data analysis and visualization tool developed and maintained. It provides dashboards, datasets, and reports that are the heart of Power BI. They enable users to create personalized dashboards combining cloud-born and on-premises data in a single view. It also allows monitoring the most important data enterprise-wide and from all their business apps. So, we can say that Power BI has a great impact on business intelligence and data analysis.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "13) Is Power BI free to use or paid?",
        "answer": "Power BI has two versions to use. Users can use the Power BI free version for free. However, there is also a Power BI Pro subscription version, which can be purchased from Microsoft Store. The purchased subscription provides an enhanced version of various features available with the free Power BI account. Most business users use the subscribed account as it offers more data refreshers per day and other features than the free version.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "14) Is Power BI better than Tableau?",
        "answer": "Both Power BI and Tableau allow the users to connect to distinct data sources. If we compare both, we find Tableau provides better support to connect to a different data warehouse than Power BI. On the other hand, Power BI is heavily integrated with Microsoft's portfolio, like the Azure cloud platform.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "15) Is Power BI a better option than Microsoft's Excel?",
        "answer": "Yes. Power BI is a more powerful tool as compared to Microsoft Excel. Power BI is easy to use and is much more flexible, while Microsoft Excel is not so handy to use. Power BI is mostly used for data visualization and dashboard sharing too many users, while Microsoft Excel is mostly used for in-depth driver analysis.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "16) Is there a way to export from power BI to Microsoft Excel?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can export any dashboard or visual data from power BI to Microsoft Excel. To export your data, choose the ellipses (3 dots) in the top-right side of any visualization and choose the icon: Export data. Your data is exported as an a.CSV file. You can even save and open the file in Excel.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "17) What are the differences between Power BI and Tableau?",
        "answer": "Tableau and Power BI are both unique tools to visualize the data. Power BI is best for applying visuals and modifying the data, while Tableau is best if you want to visualize the data only. Let's compare both of them:\nFeature Power BI Tableau\nData Visualization Power BI mainly focuses on modeling and reporting. It is much easier to upload data sets with Power BI. It provides drag and drops features to make your work easier and effective. Tableau is the best tool for data visualization.\nCost Power BI is cheaper than Power BI. Tableau is costlier when compared to Power BI.\nDeployment Power BI comes only with the SaaS model. Tableau provides more flexible and easily customizable features. It is available in both models, such as on-premises and cloud.\nData Analysis Power BI provides an in-depth analysis of the data because it allows us to create the relationships between the data sources. Tableau provides highly capable features that enable users to deal with real-time trends in effective data usage.\nData Handling Power BI is slow to handle vast volumes of data because it needs direct connections. Tableau is best for handling massive data sets and vast volumes of data.\nUser Interface The User Interface of Power Bi is simple and easy to use. Tableau uses a customized dashboard as a user interface.\nCustomer Support and Community Although Microsoft introduces power BI, it has a smaller community than Tableau due to its late entry into the market. Tableau has a bigger community.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "18) Is Business Intelligence a Good Career Option?",
        "answer": "Business Intelligence is one of the greatest career options nowadays. One of the biggest reasons for choosing a career in Business Intelligence is the on-demand outlook. According to the US Bureau of Labor Statistics report, the demand for expert BI managers and analysts is expected to leap to 14% by 2026, with the overall need for data professionals to climb to 28% by 2020.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "19) Is Power BI hard to use for a beginner?",
        "answer": "It doesn't require writing SQL code in Power BI like other BI tools. If you have good MS Excel knowledge, you can use this tool easily. It just requires a bit of MS Excel knowledge.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "20) What is the cost of Power BI?",
        "answer": "Power BI comes with mainly three versions: Power BI Desktop, Power BI and Power BI pro.\nHere, Power BI Desktop and Power BI are free of cost. If you want to use the Power BI Pro, you have to pay $9.99 per month after a 60-day free trial.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "21) What is the difference between Power BI and Power BI Pro?",
        "answer": "Power BI provides some limited features to allow us to get started searching for data in a completely new way. On the other hand, Power BI Pro comes with some additional features like scheduling data, live data sources, storage capacity, along with complete interactivity and much more.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "22) What do you mean by the term Power BI Desktop?",
        "answer": "Power BI Desktop is a free business intelligence app. It is used to install on the computer system to work with the Power BI services. It offers shaping, modeling, data exploration, and report creation using high interactive visualizations. It also allows us to save all our work to a file to publish reports and data to the Power BI site that we can share with others too.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "23) In how many formats Power BI is available in the market?",
        "answer": "Power BI is available in 3 formats:\nPower BI Desktop: This format is used for desktop computers.\nPower BI service: This is an online SaaS (Software as a Service).\nMobile Power BI apps: This format is used for iOS and Android mobile devices.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "24) Is there any online support available for Power BI for mobile devices?",
        "answer": "Yes, Power BI supports mobile devices. You can download Power BI apps for iOS devices, Windows 10 devices, and Android smartphones. These Power BI apps can be installed from the below app stores:\nGoogle Play\nApple Store\nWindows Store",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "25) What are the main Building blocks of Power BI?",
        "answer": "The main building blocks of Power BI are:\nVisualizations\nData Sets\nReports\nDashboard\nTiles",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "26) What is Visualization in Power BI?",
        "answer": "Visualization is a process of Power BI used to represent data in pictorial form like tables, graphs or charts based on the specific requirement.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "27) What is a Report in Power BI?",
        "answer": "The Report is a feature of Power BI, resulting from visualized data from a single data set. A report can contain multiple pages of visualization.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "28) What are the data sources that support and connect to Power BI?",
        "answer": "The following data sources support DirectQuery in Power BI:\nAmazon Redshift\nAzure SQL Database\nAzure Data Explorer\nAtScale (Beta)\nAzure HDInsight Spark\nGoogle BigQuery\nAzure SQL Data Warehouse\nHDInsight Interactive Query",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "29) What are the basic system requirements before using Power BI?",
        "answer": "Before using the Power BI service for free, we must have a working email and a web browser installed on our system. By using this, we can easily explore data and create reports on Power BI Desktop. Go to the following store to download the Power BI mobile app:\nGoogle Play\nApp Store\nWindows Store",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "30) What is the difference between SUM() and SUMX() in Power BI?",
        "answer": "Sum() specifies the sum function that takes the data columns and aggregates it totally, while SumX() specifies the SumX function that makes you able to filter the data you want to add.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "31) What is the CORR function in Power BI, and when is it used?",
        "answer": "CORR() is a correlation function used to provide a correlation between two distinct variables ranging from -1 to 1.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "32) What do you understand by Power View?",
        "answer": "Power View is a data visualization technique used to create interactive graphs, charts, maps and other visuals that makes your data more interactive. It is available in Excel, SQL Server, SharePoint, and Power BI.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "33) What are the main advantages of Power BI?",
        "answer": "Following is the list of top advantages of Power BI:\nPower BI can be integrated well with any existing application.\nPower BI contains rich and personalized Dashboards.\nBy using Power BI, you can securely publish reports.\nPower BI provides quick access to data, which means there is no speed and memory issue.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "34) What are the biggest disadvantages or drawbacks of using Power BI?",
        "answer": "Following is the list of main disadvantages or drawbacks of Power BI:\nPower BI does not mix imported data, which you have accessed from real-time connections.\nPower BI cannot accept file sizes larger than 1 GB.\nPower BI contains a dashboard that does not accept or pass user, account, or other entity parameters.\nIn Power BI, dashboards and reports can only be shared with users having similar email domains.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "35) Which programming language is used in Power Query?",
        "answer": "A new programming language called M programming language or M-Code is used in a power query.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "36) What do you understand by the term 'M language' in Power BI?",
        "answer": "M language is a programming language used in Power Query. It is a functional, case-sensitive and easy to use language. It is pretty similar to other programming languages.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "37) What do you understand by the term responsive slicers?",
        "answer": "Responsive slicer is used to save the space on the report page. It is very easy to resize a responsive slicer to various sizes and shapes on a report page. The data contained on it is also rearranged according to it. If the visual becomes too small, an icon representing the visual ability takes its place. So, it also saves space on the report page.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "38) What information we need to have to create a map in Power Map?",
        "answer": "We need to have some location data such as city, state, country or latitude and longitude to create a map in Power Map. This is required because power Maps are used to display geographical visualizations.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "39) What are the important features of the Power BI dashboard?",
        "answer": "Following is the list of Power BI dashboard:\nPower BI dashboard facilitates you to go through the page, bookmarks, and selection pane.\nPower BI dashboard allows you to create various tiles like web content, images, textbox, and integrate URLs.\nYou can also set the report layout to mobile view by using the Power BI dashboard.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "40) How would you analyze Power BI reports data in Microsoft excel?",
        "answer": "You have to follow the steps given below to analyze Power BI reports data in Microsoft excel:\nFirst, open the Power BI Admin portal, go to tenant settings, and select -> Analyze.\nCheck if Power BI Administrator has enabled the Excel option or not.\nGo to the upper right corner, click settings to download and install Excel updates.\nGo to the left-hand side navigation pane, go to the workspace, click on the dataset, click on Eclipses (three dots) and select Analyze in Excel.\nDownload the ODC file, save, and double click on it.\nAt last, you have to provide a power BI user id and password.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "41) What is the data source filter in Power BI?",
        "answer": "A data source filter is used to filter the data before loading it into machines. It is a parameter used for data filtering.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "42) What is the difference between older and newer Power BI?",
        "answer": "The new Power BI tool contains a new design tool known as Power BI Desktop. It is a standalone designer, including Power Pivot, Power View and Power Query in the back end. On the other hand, the older Power BI contains excel add-ins. Besides this, there are several graphs available, including treemap, line area chart, waterfall, combo chart, etc., in the newer Power BI version.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "43) What do you understand by the on-premise gateway in Power BI?",
        "answer": "In Power BI, the on-premise gateway works as a bridge that helps transfer the data safely and securely, which is on-premise (not on the cloud).",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "44) What is the meaning of the term data alerts in Power BI?",
        "answer": "In Power BI, the data alerts only work on data that is refreshed. When you refresh the data, the Power BI looks to see if an alert is set for that data or not. If the data has reached an alert threshold, it triggers an alert.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "45) What is the use of the split function in Power BI?",
        "answer": "In Power BI, the split function is used to split the string database on the given delimiter.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "46) What are the main differences between Power BI personal Gateway and Data Management Gateway?",
        "answer": "The Power BI Personal Gateway is used for reports that are deployed in Powerbi.com. On the other hand, a data management gateway is an app installed on the gateway on source data machines to deploy reports on Sharepoint and schedule to refresh automatically.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "47) What do you understand by Power BI Designer?",
        "answer": "Power BI Designer is a standalone app used to create Power BI reports and upload them to Powerbi.com. It is a combination of Power Bi components i.e., Power View, Power Pivot, and Power Query.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "48) What are KPIs in Power BI?",
        "answer": "KPIs stands for Key Performance Indicators. KPIs are used to evaluate the organization's performance in distinct areas by evaluating measurable goals and values. A KPI contains a measure or base value evaluated against target values and compares the performance with the target. KPI is also used to help you to evaluate the analysis performances with their graphical representation and specifies if your goals have been met or not.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "49) What is the difference between Distinct() and Values() in DAX?",
        "answer": "Generally, the Distinct() and Values() functions are the same in Power BI. The only difference between them is that the Values() function don't calculate null values, whereas the Distinct() function calculates even the null values.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "50) What are the advantages of the direct query method in Power BI?",
        "answer": "The Power BI desktop supports data visualizations on smaller sets. Its limit is a maximum of 1 GB. But the Direct Query Method facilitates the user to build huge data sets and data visualizations. There is no limit to the dataset for the direct query method, and a 1GB dataset limit is not applicable in this method.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "51) What is the incremental refresh in the context of Power BI?",
        "answer": "Incremental refresh is used to refresh the newly added data to avoid truncating and loading data.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "52) What is the difference between a Filter and a Slicer?",
        "answer": "Filters are used to restrict users and not allow them to interact with dashboards or reports, while the slicers are used to interact with dashboards and reports.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "53) What are the different tabs in the Reports development Window?",
        "answer": "The three main tabs in the Reports development Window are as follows:\nRelationship tab\nData Modeling Tab\nReport Tab",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "54) How many types of default Graphs (Visualizations) are available in Power BI?",
        "answer": "There are around 26 types of default Graphs (Visualizations) are available in Power BI.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "55) What is the difference between a new column and a new measure in Power BI?",
        "answer": "In Power BI, a new column is an area where the physical data is stored when logic is applied. On the other hand, the measure is where the calculations are performed on the fly based on dimensions. The measure doesn't store any physical data like Column.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "56) What are the different joins in Power BI?",
        "answer": "There are mainly two types of joins in Power BI:\nHorizontal Joins: Horizontal Joins are used to append data from multiple tables.\nVertical Joins: Vertical Joins are used to merge the data from multiple tables.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "57) Is there any way to dynamically change the value measure to show multiple measures?",
        "answer": "Yes. You can dynamically change the value measure to show multiple measures using the harvesting measure and switch function.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "58) What is the need of signing up with a business email in Power BI?",
        "answer": "Power BI does not support the email address given by telecommunications or consumer email service providers. That's why we need to sign up with a business email.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "59) What is the usage of statewith() in Power BI?",
        "answer": "In Power BI, the statewith() function returns the logical answers TRUE if the sub-string is the starting string for the superstring. If it is not, it will return false.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "60) What is the Embed Code in Power BI?",
        "answer": "The Embed code is an option in the Power BI service. It is used to generate a link address for the Power BI report and can also be shared across clients.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "61) What is the Time Intelligence function in Power BI?",
        "answer": "In Power BI, the time intelligence function is used to manipulate data using periods.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    },
    {
        "question": "62) How can you hide and unhide a specific report in Power BI?",
        "answer": "Follow the steps given below to hide and unhide a specific report in Power BI:\nGo to the menu bar.\nChoose Selection pane.\nSelect hide/unhide the report.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "power-bi"
    }
]